Finding Aid for the Ralph J. Bunche papers LSC.2051
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Organizations and Associations, 1935-1967; 54 boxes
  - University of Pittsburgh, Advisory Committee on Residential Seminars on World Affairs. Correspondence regarding committee, 1959 (Box 336, Folder 8)
  - University of the State of New York, Citizens Advisory Council on the Readjustment of the High School Program. Meeting notices and agendas, 1949-1951 (Box 337, Folder 1)
  - Westinghouse Time Capsule, Selections Committee. Reports and recommendations, 1964 (Box 337, Folder 2)
  - Westinghouse Time Capsule, Selections Committee. Reports and recommendations, 1965 (Box 337, Folder 3)
  - Westinghouse Time Capsule, Selections Committee. Reports and recommendations, 1965 (Box 337, Folder 4)
  - Wheel of Fortune Hero of the Year, Committee Judge. Stories of candidates, 1953 (Box 337, Folder 5)
  - White House Conference on Education, Committee. Meeting notices and correspondence regarding committee, 1954 (Box 337, Folder 6)
  - White House Conference on Education, Committee. Meeting notices and correspondence regarding committee (1 of 2), 1955 (Box 337, Folder 7)
  - White House Conference on Education, Committee. Meeting notices and correspondence regarding committee (2 of 2), 1955 (Box 338, Folder 1)
    Includes event folder.
  - White House Conference on Education, Committee. Meeting notices and correspondence regarding committee, 1956 (Box 338, Folder 2)
  - White House Conference on Education, Sub-Committee on Teachers, 1955-1956 (Box 338, Folder 3)
  - Woodrow Wilson Foundation, Board of Directors. Meeting notices and correspondence regarding foundation (Box 338, Folder 4)
  - Woodrow Wilson Foundation, Board of Directors. Meeting notices and correspondence regarding foundation, 1951-1956 (Box 338, Folder 5)
  - World Veterans Federation, Honorary Member. Meeting notices, invitations, and correspondence regarding federation, 1958-1964 (Box 338, Folder 6)
    Includes credo authored by Ralph J. Bunche.
  - World Veterans Federation, Honorary Member. Meeting notices, invitations, and correspondence regarding federation, 1952-1957 (Box 339, Folder 1)
  - World Veterans Federation, Honorary Member. Meeting notices, invitations, and correspondence regarding federation, 1951-1952 (Box 339, Folder 2)
- Speeches, Interviews, and Broadcasted Recordings, 1926-1969; 54 boxes
  This series consists of Bunche's original speeches, academic lectures, commencement addresses and remarks given at events and recorded interviews and statements that were broadcast on radio or television programs. In many cases manuscript drafts, reading copies, and transcripts with annotations and marginalia exist for speeches and broadcasts. Folders often include correspondence and supporting documents related to the event where the speech took place, including programs and reprints. Acceptance speeches for honorary degrees and awards are also included in this series. Some recordings of interviews and television broadcasts, including Bunche's Person to Person interview with Edward R. Murrow, are housed with the Film and Audio Recordings 1937-1975 series.
  Materials are arranged in chronological order, with speaking engagement schedules and general materials related to broadcasted recordings at the beginning of each year.
  - "That Man May Dwell in Peace," UCLA, oratorial contest, 1926 (Box 339, Folder 3, Box 43)
    - Speech, "That man may dwell in peace", UCLA oratorical contest, Spring 1926
  - "Young Negro," Los Angeles, speech, 1927 (Box 339, Folder 4)
    - Speech, "The young Negro", given in Los Angeles (draft), 1926 or 1927
      Handwritten speech
  - "Negro Political Laboratories," National Municipal League, speech, 1928 October 16 (Box 339, Folder 5)
  - "The Courageousness of the Commonplace," Randall Junior High School, speech, 1929 June 18 (Box 339, Folder 6)
  - "Gandhi and the Future of India," College Alumnae Club of D.C., speech, 1930 December 20 (Box 339, Folder 7)
  - "Some Observations of a Faculty Member on Universities," Howard Club of Philadelphia, speech, 1935 March 2 (Box 339, Folder 8)
  - "The Power of Non-Violence," Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, panel discussion, 1935 March 16 (Box 339, Folder 9)
  - "Futility of Racialism in a Period of Social Change," City-Wide Young People's Forum, speech, 1935 March 24 (Box 339, Folder 10)
  - "Modern Policies of Imperialistic Administration of Subject Peoples," Howard University Minorities Conference, speech, 1935 April 5 (Box 339, Folder 11)
  - "Critique of New Deal Social Planning as it Affects Negroes," Howard University, speech, 1935 May 20 (Box 339, Folder 12)
    Includes program.
  - "French and British Imperialism in West Africa," Association for the Study of Negro Life and History, speech, 1935 September 9 (Box 339, Folder 13)
    Includes program with handwritten notes.
  - "Education and Minority Group Citizenship," Miner Teachers College, speech, 1935 November 13 (Box 339, Folder 14)
  - "Academic Freedom," Capital City Forum, speech, 1935 November 22
  - "Imperialism in West Africa," Capital Pleasure Club, speech, 1935 December 14 (Box 339, Folder 16)
  - Scottsboro Defense Address, Mass meeting, speech, 1936 February 10 (Box 339, Folder 17)
    - Speech, Scottsboro rally, Vermont Ave. Baptist Church (draft), 1936 February 10
      Handwritten points to address in speech.
    - Save the Scottsboro Boys; flyer, 1936 February 10
      Flyer announcing a rally in support of the "Scottsboro Boys." Ralph Bunche was one of the featured speakers at the rally.
  - "Realism and the 'Negro Problem'," City-Wide Young People's Forum, speech, 1936 March 22 (Box 339, Folder 18)
  - "Some Facts on the Economic Conditions of Teachers," Representing Inter-Professional Association, Senate hearing, 1936 April 15 (Box 339, Folder 19)
  - "Socio-Economic Aspects of Racial Conflict," Young Friends Movement, speech, 1936 April 25 (Box 339, Folder 20)
  - "Politico-Economic Analysis of the Problems of Race," Detroit Civic Rights Committee, speech, 1936 May 24 (Box 340, Folder 1)
  - "Fascism and Minority Groups," NAACP Annual Conference, speech, 1936 July 2 (Box 340, Folder 2)
  - "Some Implications of Economic Status of the American Negro," Princeton University, speech, 1936 October 27 (Box 340, Folder 3)
  - "Negro in America," Northwestern University, Radio broadcast, 1936 November 15 (Box 340, Folder 4)
    Radio program with Melville Herskovitz.
  - "Some Historical and Psychological Factors in Status of the American Negro," Northwestern University, speech, 1936 December 9 (Box 340, Folder 5)
  - "The French Mandate Togo," Northwestern University, speech, 1937 January 6 (Box 340, Folder 6)
  - "The Status of the Negro in the U.S.," Institute of Education, speech, 1937 June 11 (Box 340, Folder 7)
  - "The Negro in American Society," Princeton University, speech, 1938 October 17 (Box 340, Folder 8)
  - "The Land Equation in Kenya Colony (As Seen By a Kikuyu Chief)," Association of Negro History, speech, 1938 November 12 (Box 340, Folder 9)
  - "Race Relations--South African and American," Northwestern University Student Congress, speech, 1938 December 9 (Box 340, Folder 10)
  - "Some Aspects of the Political Status of African and American Negroes," Kentucky State College, speech, 1939 February 12 (Box 340, Folder 11)
  - "Social Attitudes, the Constitution and the Courts," Association of Social Science Teacher in Negro Colleges, speech, 1939 March 11 (Box 340, Folder 12)
  - "Race Relations--South African and American," Howard University Faculty Wives, speech, 1939 March 19 (Box 340, Folder 13)
  - "Parallels Between Problems of Native Peoples of Africa and the American Negro," Morgan College, speech, 1939 March 22 (Box 340, Folder 14)
    - Speech, given at Morgan College, relating observations on the status of the Negro in French and British colonial Africa (draft), 1939
      Hand-written speech
  - "The Irua Ceremony Among the Kikuyu of Kiambu District, Kenya," University of Pennsylvania Anthropological Society, speech, 1939 April 14 (Box 340, Folder 15)
  - "Techniques for Minority Group Action," New Negro Alliance, speech, 1939 April 23 (Box 340, Folder 16)
  - "Will a British Victory Achieve a Democratic World Order?," Howard University, speech, 1940 May 15 (Box 340, Folder 17)
  - "The Role of the University in Political Orientation," Howard University Conference on the Needs of Negro Youth, speech, 1940 July 16 (Box 340, Folder 18)
  - "The Framework for a Course in Negro History," Hunter College, speech, 1940 December 4 (Box 340, Folder 19)
  - "The Negro's Stake in the Present World Crisis," Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools for Negroes, speech, 1940 December 6 (Box 340, Folder 20)
  - "An Analysis of the Dynamics and Mechanisms of Negro Disenfranchisement," American Political Science Association, speech, 1940 December 27 (Box 340, Folder 21)
  - "Observations on Black and White Thinking on Thinking on the Negro Problem," Howard University Conference on Adult Education and the Negro, speech, 1941 January 31 (Box 340, Folder 22)
  - "An Analysis of Contemporary Negro Leadership," Saint Augustine's College, speech, 1941 February 8 (Box 341, Folder 1)
  - "The Negro's Stake in the World Crisis," Shaw University, speech, 1941 February 9 (Box 341, Folder 2)
    - Speech, "The Negro's stake in the world crisis", Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools for Negroes, Montgomery, Alabama, 1940 December 6
      Signed: Ralph J. Bunche, Dept. of Political Science, Howard University.
  - "World Problems and the Negro," Lincoln University, speech, 1941 February 18 (Box 341, Folder 3)
    Includes handwritten edits.
  - "What Intolerances Threaten American Democracy?," Northwestern University, speech, 1941 February 20 (Box 341, Folder 4)
  - "Native Policy in Africa and the Dutch East Indies," Dubois Circle Club, speech, 1941 April 15 (Box 341, Folder 5)
  - "Ethnic Problems in Post-War World," Canadian Institute on Public Affairs, speech, 1943 August 28 (Box 341, Folder 6)
  - "Notes on the Importance of an International Security Organization," Southern Conference for Human Welfare, speech, 1945 January 22 (Box 341, Folder 7)
  - "The Dependent Territories Round Tables at Hot Springs," Council on world Affairs, speech, 1945 February 3 (Box 341, Folder 8)
  - "State Department Assignment," All-American News Reel, interview, 1945 March 1 (Box 341, Folder 9)
  - "Human Relations Public Meetings," Business and Professional Women's League of Washington, address, 1945 March 8 (Box 341, Folder 10)
  - Los Angeles Urban League, untitled address, 1945 June 24 (Box 341, Folder 11)
  - Center for International Understanding, untitled speech, 1945 June 27 (Box 341, Folder 12)
  - Los Angeles Town Hall, International Relations Section, untitled speech, 1945 June 28 (Box 341, Folder 13)
  - Pacific Town Club, untitled speech, 1945 June 29 (Box 341, Folder 14)
  - "Trusteeship and Non-Self-Governing Territories in the Charter of the United Nations," American Association for the United Nations, speech, 1945 December 14 (Box 341, Folder 15)
  - West Indian Conference, untitled statement, 1946 February 21 (Box 341, Folder 16)
  - Panel on Mandates and International Trusteeship, American Political Science Association, untitled speech, 1946 March 29 (Box 341, Folder 17)
  - "The Problem of the Non-Self-Governing Peoples," Mount Holyoke College, speech, 1946 April 4 (Box 341, Folder 18)
  - "Colonies and the United Nations Charter," New York Society for Ethical Culture, speech (Box 341, Folder 19)
  - "The Carribean Commission," School of Advanced International Studies, 1946 April 22 (Box 341, Folder 20)
  - "International Approach to the Problem of the Non-Self-Governing Peoples," Northwestern University, speech, 1946 April 25 (Box 341, Folder 21)
  - "Fundamental Freedoms and Non-Self-Governing Peoples," Methodist Women, address, 1946 May 1 (Box 341, Folder 22)
  - Banneker Junior High School, commencement address, 1946 June 19 (Box 341, Folder 23)
  - "Remarks on U.S. Policy Respecting Trusteeship and Self-Government for Dependent Areas," Foreign Policy Association, speech, 1946 June 26 (Box 341, Folder 24)
  - "Dependent Peoples and the UN Trusteeship Council," Catholic Association for International Peace, speech, 1946 June 26 (Box 341, Folder 25)
  - American Association for the United Nations, untitled address, 1949 July 3 (Box 341, Folder 26)
  - "International Approach to the Problem of the Non-Self-Governing Peoples," Antioch College, lecture (Box 341, Folder 27)
  - Liberian Centennial Meeting, Howard University, untitled speech, 1946 July 26 (Box 341, Folder 28)
  - Round-table on Palestine, Canadian Institute, untitled speech, 1946 August 17 (Box 342, Folder 1)
  - "International Trusteeship and Accountability: The Problem of Colonies," Canadian Institute on Public Affairs, address, 1946 August 21 (Box 342, Folder 2)
  - "Our Foreign Policy: Trusteeship and Dependent Territories," NBC University of the Air, speech (Box 342, Folder 3)
  - "Trusteeship and Accountability: the International Approach to the Colonial Problem," Wellesley College, speech, 1946 October 10 (Box 342, Folder 4)
  - "Crusade in Europe," Television broadcast, [1947] (Box 342, Folder 5)
  - Speech fragment, [1947] (Box 342, Folder 6)
  - "Thoughts on the Negro and other subjects," Association for the Study of Negro Life and History, speech, 1947 February 9 (Box 342, Folder 7)
  - "Inter-Cultural Education and Brotherhood: The Role of the Negro Teacher," Armstrong High School, speech, 1947 February 14 (Box 342, Folder 8)
  - "The International Trusteeship System," Smith College, speech, 1947 March 1 (Box 342, Folder 9)
  - "The Significance of the United Nations to Minority and Subject Peoples," Atlanta University Forum, speech (Box 342, Folder 10)
  - "Human Relations in a Modern World," City College of New York, speech, 1947 March 31 (Box 342, Folder 11)
  - "U.S. Responsibility Toward Colonial Peoples," Society for Ethical Culture, speech, 1947 April 13 (Box 342, Folder 12)
  - "The United Nations and the Colonial Problem," Howard University, speech, 1947 May 2 (Box 342, Folder 13)
  - "The Future of Dependent Peoples as Envisaged by the United Nations," Bowdoin College, lecture, 1947 May 19 (Box 342, Folder 14)
  - Lincoln University, commencement address, 1947 June 3 (Box 342, Folder 15)
  - "Some International Implications of Racial Problems," Armstrong-Hemenway Foundation, speech, 1947 October 23 (Box 342, Folder 16)
  - "The United Nations and the Colonial Problem," Brown University, speech, 1947 November 5 (Box 343, Folder 1)
  - "An International Bill of Rights," Fisk University, speech, 1947 November 8 (Box 343, Folder 2)
  - "The United Nations and Under-Privileged Peoples," Howard University, speech, 1948 February 11 (Box 343, Folder 3)
  - "Dependent Peoples and the UN Trusteeship Council," League for Mutual Aid, remarks, 1948 February 14 (Box 343, Folder 4)
  - "U.N. Approach to Minority Peoples," Eastern Sociological Society, speech, 1948 April 24 (Box 343, Folder 5)
  - Cheyney Training School for Teachers, commencement address, 1948 May 25 (Box 343, Folder 6)
  - "Prospects for Peace in Palestine," CBS, broadcast, 1948 December 27 (Box 343, Folder 7)
  - "The Palestine Problem," Overseas Writers Luncheon, speech, 1948 December 29 (Box 343, Folder 8)
  - "Remarks on Human Rights," Alpha Kappa Alpha, speech, 1948 December 29 (Box 343, Folder 9)
  - "United Nations Intervention in Palestine," American Political Science Association, speech, 1948 December 30 (Box 343, Folder 10)
  - Speaking Engagement Schedule, 1949 (Box 343, Folder 11)
  - "Memo from Lake Success," United Nations Radio, broadcast, 1949 April 23 (Box 343, Folder 12)
  - "Prospects of Peace for Palestine," CBS, broadcast, 1949 April 24 (Box 343, Folder 13)
  - "We the People," CBS, broadcast, 1949 April 26 (Box 343, Folder 14)
  - "The United Nations Effort Toward Peace in Palestine," New York Town Hall, lecture, 1949 April 27 (Box 343, Folder 15)
  - American Association for United Nations, untitled address, 1949 May 9 (Box 343, Folder 16)
  - One World Award Committee, statement, 1949 May 11 (Box 344, Folder 1)
  - Mrs. Roosevelt's Radio Program, interview, 1949 May 12 (Box 344, Folder 2)
  - "The United Nations Effort Toward Peace in Palestine," Amherst College, lecture, 1949 May 13 (Box 344, Folder 3)
  - Lincoln Center, Red Feather Service, remarks, 1949 May 16 (Box 344, Folder 4)
  - "The Human Factor in the Development of International Understanding," Colgate University, lecture, 1949 May 20 (Box 344, Folder 5)
  - Woman of Tomorrow, WJZ broadcast, interview, 1949 May 25 (Box 344, Folder 6)
  - Father's Day Luncheon, National Father's Day Committee, remarks, 1949 May 26 (Box 344, Folder 7)
  - "The United Nations Effort Toward Peace in Palestine," Williams College, lecture, 1949 May 27 (Box 344, Folder 8)
  - Fisk University, commencement address, 1949 May 30 (Box 344, Folder 9)
  - Trustee Dinner, Howard University, remarks, 1949 June 3 (Box 344, Folder 10)
  - "United Nations Intervention in Palestine," Philadelphia World council, speech, 1949 June 6 (Box 344, Folder 11)
  - National Council of Christians and Jews, dinner address, 1949 June 9 (Box 344, Folder 12)
  - "A Personal Chronicle," Reveille Club Dinner, remarks, 1949 June 11 (Box 344, Folder 13)
  - "The Road to Peace: The United Nations Way," Oberlin College, commencement address, 1949 June 13 (Box 344, Folder 14)
  - "The Outlook for Peace," Westtown School, commencement address, 1949 June 15 (Box 344, Folder 15)
  - "Lecture to UN Secretariat," lecture outline, 1949 June 16 (Box 344, Folder 16)
  - "The American Press and the Palestine Mediation Mission," Negro Publishers Association, speech, 1949 June 17 (Box 344, Folder 17)
  - Closing Convocation, Brandeis University, speech, 1949 June 19 (Box 344, Folder 18)
  - Commencement Exercises, Harvard Alumni Association Meeting, speech, 1949 June 23 (Box 344, Folder 19)
  - "United Nations Intervention in Palestine," Chicago Council on Foreign Relations, speech, 1949 June 27 (Box 345, Folder 1)
  - Northwestern University, untitled lecture, 1949 June 28 (Box 345, Folder 2)
  - "What the U.N. is Trying to do in Palestine," Minneapolis Rotary Club, speech, 1949 June 30 (Box 345, Folder 3)
  - American Association for the United Nations, University of Minnesota, untitled address, 1949 June 30 (Box 345, Folder 4)
  - Madan Rodeo, remarks, 1949 July 4 (Box 345, Folder 5)
  - National Urban League, Seattle, remarks, 1949 July 6 (Box 345, Folder 6)
  - Seattle World Affairs Council, untitled speech, 1949 July 6 (Box 345, Folder 7)
  - "The United Nations and Human Rights," Seattle World Affairs Council, speech, 1949 July 7 (Box 345, Folder 8)
  - "The Road to Peace; The United Nations Way," Seattle dinner, speech, 1949 July 7 (Box 345, Folder 9)
  - Tacoma World Affairs Council, untitled remarks, 1949 July 8 (Box 345, Folder 10)
  - "U.N. Intervention in the Palestine Dispute," Redwood City council for Civic United and Palo Alto Fair Play Committee, speech, 1949 July 11 (Box 345, Folder 11)
  - American Association for United Nations, San Francisco, untitled address, 1949 July 12 (Box 345, Folder 12)
  - "The Road to Peace: The United Nations," Stanford University, speech, 1949 July 12 (Box 345, Folder 13)
  - "Voice of the People," radio recording, 1949 July 13 (Box 345, Folder 14)
  - World Affairs Council of Northern California, untitled speech, 1949 July 14 (Box 345, Folder 15)
  - Spingarn Medal Award, NAACP Annual Conference, acceptance speech, 1949 July 17 (Box 345, Folder 16)
  - Town Hall, Los Angeles, speech, 1949 July 18 (Box 345, Folder 17)
  - Award Luncheon, UCLA, remarks, 1949 July 21 (Box 345, Folder 18)
  - Luncheon, Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, remarks, 1949 July 22 (Box 345, Folder 19)
  - "United Nations and Its Way to Peace," UCSB, speech, 1949 July 28 (Box 345, Folder 20)
  - Interview, KDB, radio broadcast, 1949 July 29 (Box 345, Folder 21)
  - Horace Heidt Show, radio recording, 1949 July 31 (Box 345, Folder 22)
  - Untitled script, News Research Service, television recording, 1949 August 18 (Box 345, Folder 23)
  - Homecoming United Nations Rally, Shrine Auditorium, speech, 1949 August 18 (Box 346, Folder 1)
  - "The Road to Peace," California State Bar Convention, speech, 1949 August 31 (Box 346, Folder 2)
  - Acceptance speech, Temple University, remarks, 1949 October 4 (Box 346, Folder 3)
  - Untitled speech, Central Queens Allied Civic Council, remarks, 1949 October 11 (Box 346, Folder 4)
  - "The United Nations Palestine Mission," Community Church of New York, speech, 1949 October 16 (Box 346, Folder 5)
  - "Education for the World of Today," University of the State of New York, speech, 1949 October 21 (Box 346, Folder 6)
  - Omega Psi Phi, dinner remarks, 1949 October 22 (Box 346, Folder 7)
  - Untitled speech, League of Women Voters of Westchester, 1949 October 23 (Box 346, Folder 8)
  - Address, Aaronsburg Celebration, 1949 October 23 (Box 346, Folder 9)
  - Milwaukee Town Hall, speech, 1949 October 24 (Box 346, Folder 10)
  - "The United Nations Peace Effort in the Near East," Calvin Bullock Forum, speech, 1949 October 26 (Box 346, Folder 11)
  - "The United Nations Peace Effort in the Near East," Mount Holyoke College, speech, 1949 November 4 (Box 346, Folder 12)
  - "Vital Role of UN in Settlement," University of Illinois, speech, 1949 November 8 (Box 346, Folder 13)
  - Florida State Conference of Social Work, speech, 1949 November 13 (Box 346, Folder 14)
  - "What the UN is trying to do in Palestine," Annual Conference of the National Council of Negro Women, speech, 1949 November 15 (Box 347, Folder 1)
  - "The United Nations Peace Mission in Palestine," Rotary Club of New York, speech, 1949 November 17 (Box 347, Folder 2)
  - "The Road to Peace, The UN Way," Erskine Lectures at College of St. Mary, lecture, 1949 November 20 (Box 347, Folder 3)
  - "Haiti and Independence," New York City, dinner remarks, 1949 November 22 (Box 347, Folder 4)
  - "The United Nations Peace Effort," Vassar College, speech, 1949 December 2 (Box 347, Folder 5)
  - Dinner Honoring Harry Hershfield, McCosker-Hershfield Cardiac Home, remarks, 1949 December 3 (Box 347, Folder 6)
  - Chicago Council, lecture outline, 1949 December 6 (Box 347, Folder 7)
  - "UN Efforts in Palestine," Sinai Temple Forum, speech, 1949 December 6 (Box 347, Folder 8)
  - "UN Operations," Illinois Institute of Technology, assembly address, 1949 December 7 (Box 347, Folder 9)
  - North Shore Forum, remarks, 1949 December 7 (Box 347, Folder 10)
  - "The United Nations and Peace," Cooper Union Forum, speech, 1949 December 11 (Box 347, Folder 11)
  - New Haven Junior Chamber of Commerce, remarks, 1949 December 12 (Box 347, Folder 12)
  - Dillard University, address, 1949 December 15 (Box 347, Folder 13)
  - New Orleans Committee on Race Relations, remarks, 1949 December 15 (Box 347, Folder 14)
  - Drexel Award, Xavier University, acceptance speech, 1949 December 15 (Box 347, Folder 15)
  - Speaking Engagement Schedule, 1950 (Box 347, Folder 16)
  - "Can the United Nations Ensure a World at Peace?" Yale Political Union, speech, 1950 January 11 (Box 347, Folder 17)
  - Commencement, Michigan State Normal College, address, 1950 January 17 (Box 347, Folder 18)
  - "YMCA, Its Influence," Harlem YMCA, radio recording, 1950 January 26 (Box 347, Folder 19)
  - "The United Nations Peace Effort," Raleigh United Church, speech, 1950 January 30 (Box 347, Folder 20)
  - "The Challenge of Human Relations," University of Rochester, speech, 1950 February 11 (Box 348, Folder 1)
  - "Rebuttal," WOR, radio broadcast, 1950 February 12 (Box 348, Folder 2)
  - Negro Actors Guild of America, remarks, 1950 February 12 (Box 348, Folder 3)